Guide to the Fred Eggan Papers 1870-1991
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Srole, Leo, 1941-1963 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Stanley, Sam, 1961-1975 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Stanner, W. E. H., 1957-1963 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Stargardt, Janice, 1972-1974 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Steiner, Robert L., 1953 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Steward, Julian H., 1936-1967 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - Stewart, Frank H., 1972-1975 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - Stocking, George W., 1966 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Straus, Anne Terry, undated (Box 23, Folder 11)
  - Strodtbeck, Fred L., 1968 (Box 23, Folder 12)
  - Stubbs, Stanley, 1948 (Box 23, Folder 13)
  - Studies in Third World Societies, 1974-1990 (Box 23, Folder 14)
  - Sturtevant, William C., 1961-1986 (Box 23, Folder 15)
  - Suenari, Michio, 1965-1972 (Box 23, Folder 16)
  - Swadesh, Morris, 1950-1954 (Box 23, Folder 17)
  - Szanton, David L., 1973-1989 (Box 23, Folder 18)
  - T, general, 1936-1987 (Box 23, Folder 19)
  - Takaki, Michiko, 1985 (Box 23, Folder 20)
  - Talayesva, Don C., 1970-1971 (Box 23, Folder 21)
  - Tax, Sol, 1938-1986 (Box 23, Folder 22)
  - Terreson, Devin, 1990 (Box 23, Folder 23)
  - Thomas, William L., Jr., 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 24)
  - Thompson, Laura, 1944-1947 (Box 23, Folder 25)
  - Titiev, Mischa, 1946-1991 (Box 23, Folder 26)
  - Tom Stacey Publishers, 1971-1972 (Box 23, Folder 27)
  - Tucker, Sara Jones, 1936-1973 (Box 23, Folder 28)
  - Turner, Terence, 1972, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 29)
  - Tyler, Ralph, 1950-1963, 1975 (Box 23, Folder 30)
  - U, general, 1948-1985 (Box 23, Folder 31)
  - Ullman, Montague, 1962-1966 (Box 23, Folder 32)
  - United States Association of Philippine Anthropologists, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 33)
  - University of Cambridge, 1971 (Box 23, Folder 34)
  - University of Chicago, 1949-1989 (Box 23, Folder 35)
  - University of Chicago, Civil Affairs Training School, 1944-1945 (Box 23, Folder 36)
  - University of Chicago, Civil Affairs Training School, "Far East Civil Affairs Training Program--Introduction, " by Fred Eggan, manuscripts, 1943-1945 (Box 23, Folder 37)
  - University of Chicago, Committee on the Seventy-Fifth Anniversary, 1964-1965 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - University of Chicago, Committee on South Asian Studies, seminars, posters, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - University of Chicago, Committee on Southern Asian Studies, 1960-1968 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, "Ethno-History Collection, " manuscript, undated (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, "The Graduate Program, "undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, "History of the Department, " manuscripts, notes, clipping, 1951, 1955, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, administration, 1946-1991 (Box 24, Folder 8-11)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Anthro 230, a, b, c, Ethnology, Peoples of the World, course development, 1946-1960 (Box 25, Folder 1-4)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Anthro 240, Culture, Society, and the Individual in Society, course development, 1945, 1954 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Archaeology Laboratory, 1951 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Ernestine Bingham, 1928-1939 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Fay-Cooper Cole, "Notes on the History of the Department, " manuscripts, photos, undated (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, departmental history, memoranda, manuscripts, correspondence, clipping, 1929-1959 (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Division of Social Sciences, "Changes in Course Offerings, " manuscript, 1941-1942 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Fiftieth Anniversary Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Gerald Hickey, 1971-1972 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Lichstern Fund for Anthropological Research, 1925-1951, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, M.A. and Ph.D. degrees awarded, 1897-1979 (Box 26, Folder 5-6)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Norman A. McQuown, chairman, 1958-1959, 1974 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, rankings, 1963-1983 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, scrapbook, 1927-1938 (Box 27)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, slide catalogue, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Raymond T. Smith, chairman, 1976, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, Richard J. Storr, "Notes on the Early History of the Social Sciences at Chicago, " manuscript, 1954 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, strange letters, 1929-1935 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, student summer field research, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, syllabi, 1952-1966 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, undergraduate and graduate programs, manuscripts, memoranda, notes, 1959-1960 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, unidentified, Ph.D. examination, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - University of Chicago, Department of Anthropology, unidentified, "The Truth about Orals, " manuscript, undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - University of Chicago, "The Interuniversity Project for Behavioral Science Training in Yucatan, " report, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - University of Chicago, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - University of Chicago, Tuesday Club, 1962-1963 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1937-1991 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - University of California Press, 1966-1976 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - University of Hawaii, East-West Center, 1962-1964 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - University of Kentucky, 1964-1965 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - University of Madras, 1985 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - University of Minnesota, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - University of New Mexico Press, 1991 (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - University of Oxford, Institute of Social Anthropology, 1963-1966 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - University of Puerto Rico, 1947-1948 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - University of Wisconsin, Department of Anthropology, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - University of Wisconsin--Milwaukee, 1979-1980 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - United States, Board of Economic Warfare, 1942-1943 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - United States, Department of the Interior, 1943-1955, 1963 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - United States, Department of Health, Education, and Welfare, 1962, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - United States, State Department, 1942-1951 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - V, general, 1939-1986 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Villa Rojas, Alfonso, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Voegelin, Carl F., 1970-1973 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Voegelin, Erminie W., 1954-1964 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Vogt, Evon Z., 1947-1989 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - W, general, 1942-1989 (Box 29, Folder 11-12)
  - Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1964 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Wallis, W. Allen, 1963-1973 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Warner, W. Lloyd, 1963, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Warren, Chuck, 1951-1984 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Washburn, Wilcomb, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Watson, James B., 1947-1990 (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Watson, Virginia, 1948-1964 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, 1948-1986 (Box 29, Folder 20-21)
  - Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, Advisory Council, 1978-1980 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - White, Leslie A., 1946-1973 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Whiteley, Peter, 1983-1986 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Whorf, Benjamin L., 1941 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Whyte, William F., 1941 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Wiek, Fred, 1947-1949 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Wilson, Laurence L., 1947-1957 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Witherspoon, Gary J., 1968-1986 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Woodbury, Richard B., 1941-1979 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Woodrow Wilson National Fellowship Foundation, 1963 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Woods, Grace, 1952-1953 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Wright, Timothy W., 1974 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - Y, general, 1946-1985 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Yale University, 1946-1948 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Yalman, Nur, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Yengoyan, Aram A., 1959-1990 (Box 30, Folder 16-17)
  - Z, general, 1938-1990 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Zamora, Mario, 1965-1990 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified, 1943-1991 (Box 30, Folder 20)
- Series III: Figures in Anthropology
  This series has been divided into five subseries and contains items spanning the years 1895 to 1990. As a whole, this series focuses on particular individuals and their roles in the development of anthropology.
  Subseries 1: General Files, is a collection of correspondence, biographical and autobiographical manuscripts and reprints, bibliographies, memorabilia, media clippings, and obituaries. Most of the individuals represented were personally associated with Eggan as friends, colleagues, students, and teachers. Eggan himself wrote or edited many of the biographies, memoirs, and obituaries and festschriften present in this and the following subseries.
  The next four subseries highlight four key figures whose contributions to Eggan's thought and work were significant. Two of these figures, Lewis Henry Morgan (Subseries 2) and H. R. Voth (Subseries 5), were forerunners in the field whose anthropological concerns dovetailed with Eggan's. Morgan made early contributions to the study of Native American kinship and social organization, while Voth provided one of the earliest and most controversial ethnographic accounts of the Hopi. Eggan produced several important articles on Morgan's life and work, including texts for the 1964 Lewis Henry Morgan lectures at Rochester University and the 1977 Smithsonian Institution centennial of Morgan's classic Ancient Society.
  Subseries 5: The H. R. Voth Collection, contains approximately 739 photographs of daily and ceremonial Hopi life reprinted from Voth's original 1895 negatives as well as a descriptive catalogue of the prints. By 1964 the original nitrate negatives, housed at Bethel College (North Newton, Kansas), had so severely deteriorated that the Arizona State Museum had five sets of prints reproduced. These sets were distributed to the Museum of Northern Arizona, the Arizona Historical Foundation, the Arizona State Museum, the Bethel College Archives, and Fred Eggan at the University of Chicago. Note: To reproduce any of the images in Subseries 5, permission must be granted by Bethel College, holders of the original negatives.
  Subseries 3 and 4 represent A. R. Radcliffe-Brown and Edward Sapir. They are noteworthy, not only for their theoretical contributions to the discipline, but for the formative roles they played in Eggan's life as teachers and mentors. Among the Radcliffe-Brown materials are detailed class notes taken by Eggan which document the courses taught by Radcliffe-Brown during his tenure at the University of Chicago.
  - Subseries 1: General
    - American Anthropological Association, "Anthropology of Anthropologists, " session proposal, abstracts, correspondence, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Barrows, David P., "Memoirs of David Prescott Barrows, 1873-1954, " manuscript, undated (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Basehart, Harry W., funerary card, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Castaneda, Carlos, clippings, 1972-73 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Cole, Fay-Cooper, "Fay-Cooper Cole, 1881-1961, " "Fay-Cooper Cole, Architect of Anthropology, " by Fred Eggan, manuscripts, bibliography, reprints, correspondence, 1961-1962 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Cole, Fay-Cooper, bibliography, note cards, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Collier, John, "John Collier and the Indian New Deal, " "Pioneer Applied Anthropology, " "The Origins of Applied Anthropology in the United States, " by Lawrence Kelly, manuscripts, correspondence, 1977-1981 (Box 31, Folder 2-3)
    - A Career in Anthropology, " by Fred Eggan, manuscripts, ca.1983 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - A Symposium Honoring Harold C. Conklin, " American Anthropological Association, manuscripts, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Curtis, Edward S., "Edward S. Curtis, Ethnographer, " by Fred Eggan, manuscripts, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Farewell to Desks, " by John Sherwood, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Dozier, Edward P., "Edward P. Dozier, 1916-1971, " by Fred Eggan and Keith Basso, manuscript, correspondence, notes, clipping, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Evans-Pritchard, Edward Evan, reprints, correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Fallers, Lloyd A., Jr., "Lloyd Ashton Fallers Jr. 1925-1974, " by Fred Eggan, manuscript, ca.1974 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Fortes, Meyer, Wenner-Gren Foundation, Viking Fund Medalist Award nomination, correspondence, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Fox, Robert Bradford, obituary, correspondence, 1951-1985 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Kroeber, Alfred L., "A. L. Kroeber's Position, " by Wilhelm Kopper, manuscript, 1956 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - The Contributions of Francis LaFlesche, " by Margot P. Liberty, reprint, 1974 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Lévi-Strauss, Claude, Wenner-Gren Foundation, Viking Fund Medal Award, manuscript, 1966 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Lévi-Strauss, Claude, festschrift, manuscripts, correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Malinowski, Bronislaw, "Bronislaw K. Malinowski, 1884-1942, " lecture notes, undated (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Malinowski, Bronislaw, "Development of Ethnological Theories of Bronislaw Malinowski, " manuscript, outline, bibliography, undated (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Malinowski, Bronislaw, "Memorandum on the Regulation of Sexual Morality among Native Races, " by Bronislaw Malinowski, manuscript, undated (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Mead, Margaret, bibliography, clipping, undated (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Mintz, Sydney W., correspondence, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Nash, Philleo, manuscript, reprints, obituary, correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Redfield, Robert, "Robert Redfield, 1897-1958, " by Fay-Cooper Cole and Fred Eggan, manuscripts, reprints, correspondence, 1959 (Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Schmitt, Karl, "Karl Schmitt, " by Fred Eggan, manuscript, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Sharp, Lauriston, festschrift, memoranda, prospectus, correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - 1913-1958, " by Fred Eggan, manuscript, undated (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Spicer, Edward H., correspondence, obituaries, biographies, 1974-1986 (Box 32, Folder 6-7)
    - Spicer, Edward H., American Anthropological Association, A View of the World, symposium, manuscripts, correspondence, 1984-1989 (Box 32, Folder 8-9)
    - Spicer, Edward H., American Anthropological Association, "Discussion, " by Fred Eggan, lecture notes, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Spoehr, Alexander, "Alexander Spoehr, " by Vinson H. Sutlive, Jr., manuscript, correspondence, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Steward, Julian H., memorial service, manuscript, correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Julian H. Steward, " by Fred Eggan, manuscript, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Essays in Honor of Julian H. Steward, edited by Robert A. Manners, correspondence, 1962 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - "Stanley Stubbs, 1906-1959, " by Fred Eggan, manuscript, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Tax, Sol, festschrift, manuscript, correspondence, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Titiev, Mischa, "Mischa Titiev--Obituary, " by Joseph G. Jorgenson, manuscript, 1979 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Subseries 2: Lewis Henry Morgan
    - Notes, undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Then and Now, " Morgan Centennial, Smithsonian Institution, manuscript, June 14, 1977 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - "Lewis H. Morgan in Kinship Perspective, " Chapter II, manuscripts, undated (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - "Lewis H. Morgan and Cultural Evolution, " manuscripts, undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - A Reevaluation, " manuscripts, 1971 (Box 33, Folder 1)
    - "Lewis H. Morgan and the Future of the American Indian, " manuscripts, correspondence, 1965 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Reprints by and about Morgan, 1870-1971 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 3: Alfred Reginald Radcliffe-Brown
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 211, Comparative Science of Culture, 1932, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 4-5)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 357, Peoples of the South Pacific, 1932 (Box 33, Folder 6)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 358, Ethnology of Africa, 1931 (Box 33, Folder 7)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 361, Primitive Society, undated (Box 33, Folder 8)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 364, Primitive Religions, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 367, Law in Preliterate Societies, 1937 (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 370, Australian Tribes, 1931-1932 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 371, Family, Kin and Clan, 1932 (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Anthro 372, Institutions of Primitive Peoples, 1932 (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Comparative Social Economics, seminar, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Social Integration, 1932 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Notes on Radcliffe-Brown's courses at the University of Chicago, Social Organization of North American Indians, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence with A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, 1931-1956 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, obituaries, manuscript, reprints, 1955-1956 (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Review of Remarks and Inventions by Rodney Needham, manuscripts, correspondence, notes, clipping, 1974 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - A Memoir, " notes, manuscript, correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Foreword to A Natural Science of Society, by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, manuscript, 1956 (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Foreword, with E. E. Evans-Pritchard, to Structure and Function in Primitive Society, by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, manuscript, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - "Radcliffe-Brown, A. R., " manuscript, correspondence, 1970 (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - "Radcliffe-Brown, " Leaders in Modern Anthropology, correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Manuscripts and reprints by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, 1913 (Box 34, Folder 14)
    - Manuscripts and reprints by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, 1914-1929 (Box 34, Folder 15)
    - Manuscripts and reprints by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, 1930-1940 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Manuscripts and reprints by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, 1941-1942 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Manuscripts and reprints by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, 1946-1958 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Manuscripts and reprints by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, "Cosmology of the Australian Aborigines, " lecture, 1947 (Box 35, Folder 4)
    - Manuscripts and reprints by A. R. Radcliffe-Brown, "The Development of Social Anthropology, " lecture, 1936 (Box 35, Folder 5)
    - Introduction, " manuscript, 1948 (Box 35, Folder 6)
    - Berndt, Ronald M., "In Reply to Radcliffe-Brown on Australian Local Organization, " manuscript, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
    - Carstens, Peter, manuscript, correspondence, 1979 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Lévi-Strauss and Radcliffe-Brown, " manuscript, 1969 (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Evans-Pritchard, Edward Evan, "Applied Anthropology, " manuscript, 1946-1947 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Fortes, Meyer, notes, manuscripts, reprint, 1955-1968 (Box 35, Folder 11)
    - Kuper, Adam, correspondence, 1975-1981 (Box 35, Folder 12)
    - Explorations in Semiotic Anthropology, " manuscripts, 1982 (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Radcliffe-Brown, Russell and Whitehead, " manuscript, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - Singer, Milton, "The Problem of Historical Evidence and the Dialogical Selves of Radcliffe-Brown, " manuscript, undated (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Radcliffe-Brown's Legacy, " manuscript, correspondence, 1983 (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - Singer, Milton, correspondence, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - Srivinas, M. N., "Itineraries of an Indian Anthropologist, " photocopy, 1973 (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - Srivinas, M. N., "My Reminiscences of Radcliffe-Brown at Oxford, " draft, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Stocking, George W., Jr., "Chronology of A. R. Radcliffe-Brown to 1926, " photocopy, 1971-1973 (Box 35, Folder 20)
    - Comparative Sociology at Cambridge in 1910, " draft, notes, undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller Anthropology between the Wars, " manuscript, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Notes on His Lectures in Primitive Religion, University of Chicago, Winter Quarter, 1932, " Anthropology Tomorrow, reprint, 1956 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - University of Chicago, faculty seminar on Radcliffe-Brown, manuscripts, correspondence, 1973 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - A Series of Lectures in the Division of the Social Sciences, " manuscripts, 1936-1937 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - Weil, Daniel W., "A. R. Radcliffe-Brown Social Anthropologist, " student paper, 1962 (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Miscellaneous, reprints, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 4: Edward Sapir
    - Letters between Edward Sapir and A. L. Kroeber, 1905-1925, edited by Victor Golla, 1984-1985 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - "Edward Sapir, " drafts, reprint, correspondence, 1988 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - National Museum of Man, Edward Sapir Conference, Ottawa, notes, manuscripts, correspondence, 1984 (Box 36, Folder 10-11)
    - "Seminar on Sapir, " Ottawa, transcript, manuscript, notes, 1959 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Sapir materials, photocopies, undated (Box 37, Folder 1-2)
    - University of Utah, "Edward Sapir Collection, " guide, correspondence, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Subseries 5: H. R. Voth Collection
    - Voth, interview with Yokioma (1895-1896), notes, reproduction, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Voth, field notes (1895-1897), notes, reproduction, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - "H. R. Voth, Ethnologist, " catalogue essay, Voth Collection of the Fred Harvey Fine Arts Collection, Heard Museum, Phoenix, Arizona, drafts, notes, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Voth papers, Chicago Natural History Museum, Chicago, notes, correspondence, 1962 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Mennonite Historical Library, Bethel College, North Newton, Kansas, inventory, correspondence, notes, 1956-1965, 1979, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Mennonite Historical Library, "Catalogue of Prints from the H. R. Voth Collection, "undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Mennonite Historical Library, John M. Janzen, "Summary Report of the H. R. Voth Collection, "June 1962 (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Mennonite Historical Library, prints from negatives, catalog #621-2098 [please refer to the above "Catalog of Prints from the H.R. Voth Collections" for illustrative descriptions of each print], 1964 [ca. 1895]
    - H.R. Voth prints, Nos. 601-620. (Box 38, Envelope 1)
    - H.R. Voth prints, Nos. 601-620 (duplicates). (Box 38, Envelope 2)
    - H.R. Voth prints, Nos. 621-632 and 636-639. (Box 38, Envelope 3)
    - H.R. Voth prints, Nos. 650, 652-658 and 660-670. (Box 38, Envelope 4)